#### Rodion Bilka

iOS Developer

E-mail: flurryk@gmail.com Mobile: +38 093 820 47 39

## **Objective**

Seeking a Software Developer position utilizing creative mind and superb skills in developing applications through the most modern of development tools.

### **Summary**

9 years of iOS including 2 years of Mac OS development. Strong understanding how to implement Apple native multi-platform app architecture from the scratch. Ability to create maintainable and extensible code. Great experience with Objective-C and Swift, minor with C++.

#### **Education**

2014-2015	Specialist in Software Engineering, Zaporizhzhia National Technical University.
2010-2014	Bachelor in Software Engineering, Zaporizhzhia National Technical University.

## Languages

English (intermediate), Russian, Ukrainian.

## **Professional experience**

05/2020 - 07/2022, Team in UA

07/2013 - 03/2020, bMuse Ukraine LLC.

# **Projects**

Switcher.ai iOS	[link]	
Description	Unified application platform for streaming via SRT	
	protocol.	
Role	Overall app design, UI implementation, streamers core integration based on FFmpeg open library. Implement web to webview client JS custom callbacks. Basic WebView player with WebRTC protocol.	
Technologies	Foundation, UlKit, Core Graphics, AVFoundation, CoreVideo, GCD, VideoToolbox, Webkit (WKWebView), FFmpeg with SRT protocol.	
Programming languages	Swift, Objective C, Objective C++	
Rivet Remote [Link]		
Description	Application for streaming and play video using SRT protocol.	
Role	Overall app design, UI implementation, streamers core integration based on FFmpeg open library. Improve camera and audio capture mechanism, native WebSocket for send realtime stream statistics to Dashboard web application.	
Technologies	Foundation, UlKit, Core Graphics, AVFoundation, CoreVideo, GCD, VideoToolbox, FFmpeg with SRT protocol.	
Programming languages	Swift, Objective C, Objective C++	
TouchCast Rem	ote [Link]	
Description	Remote control of recording, interactive apps switch for main studio app	
Role	Overall app design, UI implementation, remote control protocol implementation with TC Studio app	
Technologies	Foundation, UlKit, Core Graphics, Core Animation, Multipeer connectivity, GCD, Core Motion	
Programming languages	Objective C	

Teamtime iOS [Link]		
Description	Realtime communication cross-platform application with sharable content, augment reality integration and remote desktop control.	
Role	Overall app design, UI implementation, WebRTC P2P and MCU services integration, realtime video recording, processing and streaming, speech to text services for internal use, augment reality features, web-socket data transport, performance optimization, junior colleagues mentorship, team leader assistant	
Technologies	Foundation, UIKit, Core Graphics, Core Animation, Core Video, Accelerate framework, AVFoundation, GCD, MediaToolbox, AVAudioEngine, Speech recognition services (Google, Apple native SpeechKit), ARKit, HLS, WebRTC client integration with MCU and P2P services, Cocoapods, Metal basics, Core Motion	
Programming languages	Swift, Objective C, Objective C++	
Teamtime MacOS [Link]		
Description	Realtime communication cross-platform application with sharable content, augment reality integration and remote desktop control.	
Role	Overall app design, UI implementation, WebRTC P2P and MCU services integration, realtime video recording, processing and streaming, web-socket data transport, performance optimization, remote desktop control	
Technologies	Foundation, Cocoa, Core Graphics, Core Animation, Core Video, Accelerate framework, AVFoundation, GCD, MediaToolbox, Speech recognition services (Google, Apple native SpeechKit), HLS, WebRTC client integration with MCU and P2P services, WebKit, Cocoapods, Metal basics	
Programming languages	Swift, Objective C, Objective C++	
TouchCast Studio [Link]		
Description	Interactive videos and realtime streaming app platform.	

Role	Overall app design, UI implementation, legacy code refactor, remote control app integration, HLS streaming implementation, performance optimization		
Technologies	Foundation, UIKit, Core Graphics, Core Animation, Multipeer connectivity, GCD, HLS		
Programming languages	Objective C		
TouchCast Memo [Link]			
Description	Simple interactive video recording application		
Role	Overall app design, UI implementation, cloud services integration, social networks integration, iOS app webcontent communication, video playback, recording and processing, social-based features		
Technologies	Foundation, UlKit, Core Graphics, Core Animation, Core Video, AVFoundation, GCD, Facebook SDK, Twitter SDK, WebKit, Cocoapods, Cloud services integration iCloud Drive, Microsoft One Drive, Google Drive, Dropbox		
Programming languages	Objective C		
Takes [Link]			
Description	Smart live photos using motion bypass filter and applicable image filters. Social network features.		
Role	Overall app design, UI implementation, social integration, video playback and live processing, local caching, photo capture and video recording.		
Technologies	Foundation, UIKit, Core Graphics, Core Animation, GCD, Facebook SDK, Twitter SDK		
Programming languages	Objective C		

Get it Hoops [Link]		
Description	A basketball-themed app with an accessory device to register goals and extended multimedia capabilities.	
Role	Overall app design, UI implementation, video recording, processing and playback, performance optimization	
Technologies	Foundation, UIKit, Core Graphics, Core Animation, Core Text, GameKit, GCD	
Programming languages	Swift, Objective C	